KEVIN LONG

Phone: 512-975-0082 | Email: kevinjlong75@gmail.com | Austin, TX LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/klong75 | Portfolio: https://kevinlong.dev GitHub: https://github.com/KLong75

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Texas at Austin and developed skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, responsive web design, and more. Bachelor of arts in theater. Has worked as a theater artist specializing in puppetry for over 20 years. A career in the arts has often necessitated a day job. Extensive work experience in a variety of roles and industries including retail, food service, agriculture, manufacturing, and education. Real world experience informs thinking as a developer resulting in applications that are effective, intuitive, and easy to use. Excellent communication skills. Adapts to evolving circumstances. Growth mindset. Proactively works to grow and improve. Thrives on creative problem solving and collaboration. Experienced at meeting deadlines under pressure.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, Mongoose, Sequelize, MySQL, Express.js, React.js, Node.js,

Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material UI, Google Search, Google Workspace, Zoom

PROJECTS

MUSICOLOGY - A MERN stack networking application for musicians.

- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/KLong75/musician-networking-app
- Deployed Application: https://musicology-umekev.herokuapp.com/
- Role: Primary author and project manager
- Tools: MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, React, Node.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, bcrypt, JSON web tokens

Movies R Us - Allows users to browse titles by genre across all major subscription streaming services and link directly to a selected title on any streaming service that carries the title.

- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/KLong75/Movies-R-Us-KJ
- Deployed Application: https://klong75.github.io/Movies-R-Us-KJ/
- Role: Javascript
- Tools: HTML, Javascript, CSS, Watch Mode API

EXPERIENCE

Theater Artist 1998 - Present Various Locations

Worked with several different theater companies in a variety of capacities including puppeteer, actor, director, technical director, lighting designer, set designer, and theater technician. Key Accomplishments:

- Performed in 18 states and 2 foreign countries (South Korea and The Dominican Republic)
- Technical Director and Staff Artist for MayDay Parade and Festival (2001 2012) annual outdoor giant puppet spectacle produced by In The Heart of the Beast Puppet and Mask Theater involving hundreds of performers attended by tens of thousands in Minneapolis, MN.
- Director for Barebones Halloween Puppet Extravaganza (2002) annual outdoor giant puppet spectacle involving hundreds of performers attended by thousands in Minneapolis, MN.
- Director for Country Day Creative Arts Festival Opening Ceremony (2007- 2011) an outdoor giant puppet spectacle involving over 100 student performers ages 7 14 in Metairie, LA.

First and Second Grade Teacher Austin Discovery School

2020 - 2021

Austin, TX

Utilized clear communication and critical thinking skills to develop and implement lesson plans for all subjects across two grade levels.

Key Accomplishment:

• Successfully developed and implemented an innovative online learning system for virtual learning. This experience led directly to an interest in coding.

Preschool Teacher Children's Discovery Center

2019 - 2020

Austin, TX

Lesson planning, supervision, care, and safety of a classroom of 12 two year old children. Keys to success were flexibility, adaptability, patience, multi-tasking, quick thinking, and a thick skin.

Manufacturer 2018 - 2019
Calton Cases Austin, TX

Fabrication and installation by hand of interiors for custom guitar, bass, banjo, mandolin, and violin cases using foam, fabric, and a variety of glues.

Procurement Supervisor University of TX, Athletics Nutrition Center

2017 - 2018

Austin, TX

Inventory management, ordering of all food and supplies, receiving orders, supervising stocking of all items received, researching new items, communicating with vendors, customer service, etc. Key Accomplishment:

• Developed and implemented an electronic ordering and inventory system.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

University of Texas

Austin, TX

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Full Stack Web Development

Bachelor of Arts in Theater Truman State University

Kirksville, MO